DAN KLEIN: Let's take a look and see
what that looks like in the demo.
All right, so here we go.
Let's look forward checking first.
All right, what's going to happen?
I'm going to start in the lower left.
I'm going to assign blue.
Then I'm going to assign red.
Then how about in the next one?
Well, I'm going to assign blue, that's
the first thing on my strike order.
And then I'm going to assign red.
Now let's stop and think.
I'm doing forward checking.
So forward checking has done its job.
It said, given your assignment, these
two variables, one up here and one
over here, both have only green
as their legal domain.
So for forward checking,
what happens next?
I keep going, right?
So I keep going.
I get to here and I assign
green, and then I fail.
So I back up and I try
it again, and I fail.
I back up a little further and
I try it again, and I fail.
And so, for forward checking, even
though we're looking into the future,
we're kind of not looking
into the future enough.
So eventually, I'll get
past this region.
This is a tricky region.
Eventually I'll backtrack
enough to get past here.
And then I'll basically kind of tear
through the rest pretty well.
So forward checking would
eventually work.
How about if we enforce arc consistency
instead of just doing
forward checking?
Well, let's see what happens here.
So I assign blue.
I assign red.
I assign blue.
Now look here.
We already know that as a consequence of
the blue and red here that we have
to have green up here.
And that means we can't
have green here.
And that means that as soon as I assign
blue here, I can see that I'm
going to have to use green
at this fourth circle.
That means we never actually get into
that thrashing where we have to
backtrack to figure out
what to do next here.
We simply assign green
and then move on.
Now just because we're doing arc
consistency doesn't mean there won't
be backtracking.
In fact, here there is a
little backtracking.
But it's much more limited
and much more local.
So arc consistency here fixed that
problem of having the violation that
we couldn't detect.